<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[One is Mine]]></title><description><![CDATA[A starter blog demonstrating what Gatsby can do.]]></description><link>https://oneismine.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 03:40:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Top 10 Shapeless Resources]]></title><description><![CDATA[Intro What is shapeless?  Well its a library for doing generic programming in Scala.  What is generic programming, well that is a little…]]></description><link>https://oneismine.com//shapeless/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://oneismine.com//shapeless/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Intro&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is shapeless?  Well its a library for doing generic programming in Scala.  What is generic programming, well that is a little harder to explain.  Generic programming is the type of polymorphism your lanugage doesn’t support.  That sounds sort of like a recurisve defintion that results in a circular definition.  Anyhow, hopefully it will all make sense by the time you get to the end of this list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://underscore.io/books/shapeless-guide/&quot;&gt;The Type Astronaut’s Guide to Shapeless Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This free ebook from underscore walks thru shapeless in some fun detail.  I recommend after reading it you attempt to build your own Json parser using the techniques learned in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/milessabin/shapeless&quot;&gt;The Shapeless Gitter channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions after reading the shapeless book. Gitter is a great place to go.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scala-exercises.org/shapeless/generic&quot;&gt;Shapeless Exercises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scala Exercises has a whole section of shapeless exercises that you can use to cement your knowledge of the shapeless library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://corecursive.com/008-generic-programming-and-shapeless-with-miles-sabin/&quot;&gt;Generic Programming and Shapeless with Miles Sabin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this interview with Miles Sabbin, the creator of shapeless, he explains why he created shapeless and also the why.  The why is actually a pretty interesting story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/build-and-learn/is-shapeless-worth-it-what-is-shapeless-anyway-900cba6b717a&quot;&gt;Is Shapeless worth it?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An article tackling whether using shapeless is worth it.  Spoiler alert, it is if you like type safey and avoid boiler plate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jto.github.io/articles/getting-started-with-shapeless/&quot;&gt;Getting Started with Shapeless&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@skaalf’s guide to getting started with shapeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/milessabin&quot;&gt;@milessabin&lt;/a&gt; Miles Sabin on twitter.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xG00ivPa9hk&quot;&gt;Code Mesh Kind PolyMorphism Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a bit of reach. But let’s say it will be intereting to those of us interested in Shapeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;9. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zt6LjUnOcFQ&quot;&gt;The Type Astronaut’s Guide to Shapeless Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wrapping up:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There we go.  So shapeless is geneic programming and generic programming is the type of polymorphism your lanuage doesn’t support.  &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Top 10 Tech Podcasts]]></title><description><![CDATA[1.  Software Engineering Daily With one episdoe a business day, and a focused format, Jeff at SEDaily is one of my favorite podcasts. My…]]></description><link>https://oneismine.com//tech-podcasts/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://oneismine.com//tech-podcasts/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Software Engineering Daily&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With one episdoe a business day, and a focused format, Jeff at SEDaily is one of my favorite podcasts. My first podcast interview was also as a guest host on SEDaily, so I can’t say enough good things about this podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Data Skeptic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how I got subscribed to data skeptic, as a I’m not a data scientist of any sort.  But I’m glad I am.  My favorite thing is the miny epsidoes where Kyle explains to ??? a concept.  I think it is very impressive that she comes to these cold, from another background and is recorded.  To me that is a frightening endevaour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;CoRecursive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my podcast.  Jeff at SEDaily gave me the format, in depth technical interviews.  I try to interview smart people about technical topics that are deep and avoid tech news and trivia.  I also try to keep it casual in tone.  Whether I succeed at all or any of these is an open question, but doing the interviews has been so much fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Mapping The Journey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if this podcast is still being made but some heavy hitters have been interviewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;.net Rocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first podcast I listened to was The Daily Source Code with Adam Curry, but mainly I recall it being about podcasts and podcasting.  .Net Rocks was as fun interview show about .net and since I had recently started writing C# for a living, I jump on this one write away.   This must have been 12 or more years ago and though I don’t listen anymore, it has to get a shout out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;The New Reustacean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris has this podcast about learning Rust.  And he just narrates it to the listener.  I think that is just such an challenging and intimate format and Chris pulls it off everytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;ScalaWags&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun group interviews about scala.  No longer being made, but a great podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;HaskellCast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very few epsidoes of this podcast were ever made, but when they were made I was pretty focused on learning haskell.  I think they should pick it back up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;9. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Functional Geekery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;10. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Hanselminutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There we go.  So shapeless is geneic programming and generic programming is the type of polymorphism your lanuage doesn’t support.  &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>